[{"num":1,"sample":"5A11","correct":"B","question":"A person holding a radiotelegraph third class operator permit is authorized to operate: ","answers":{"a":"A.Radiotelegraph stations on aircraft with power under 100 watts ","b":"B.Radiotelephone communication stations on aircraft with power under 250 watts ","c":"C.Any coastal radiotelegraph station ","d":"D.Any radiotelephone station on a ship"}},{"num":2,"sample":"5A12","correct":"C","question":"Technical adjustments to a radiotelegraph transmitter at a land station may be made by: ","answers":{"a":"A.Any representative of the station licensee ","b":"B.The holder of a restricted radiotelephone permit ","c":"C.The holder of a second class radiotelegraph license ","d":"D.Any holder of a radiotelegraph third class operator permit"}},{"num":3,"sample":"5A13","correct":"A","question":"The radio operator of a manually operated radiotelegraph station is required to: ","answers":{"a":"A.Post or have available his operator license or permit ","b":"B.Take a code examination each time his license or permit is renewed ","c":"C.Keep the station license in his personal possession at all times ","d":"D.Sign the radio log at 4hour intervals"}},{"num":4,"sample":"5A14","correct":"A","question":"When an operator license or permit has been sent to the FCC for renewal, duplication, replacement, endorsement, etc., the operator is required to exhibit at his operating place of duty in lieu of the original document: ","answers":{"a":"A.A signed copy of the application which has been filed with the FCC ","b":"B.A letter of authorization from the FCC ","c":"C.His photograph and finger prints ","d":"D.His birth certificate"}},{"num":5,"sample":"5A25","correct":"D","question":"In transmitting the radiotelegraph Urgency Signal: ","answers":{"a":"A.The signal must consist of groups of four ","b":"B.The signal must consist of groups of five ","c":"C.The signal should be sent as one character ","d":"D.The letters of each group should be clearly separated from each other"}},{"num":6,"sample":"5A26","correct":"B","question":"In radiotelegraphy the Distress signal is: ","answers":{"a":"A.IMI ","b":"B.SOS ","c":"C.XXX XXX XXX ","d":"D.CQD CQD CQD CQD CQD"}},{"num":7,"sample":"5A27","correct":"C","question":"In radiotelegraphy the Safety Signal is: ","answers":{"a":"A.XXX ","b":"B.CQD ","c":"C.TTT TTT TTT ","d":"D.IMI IMI"}},{"num":8,"sample":"5A28","correct":"D","question":"In transmitting the radiotelegraph Distress Signal: ","answers":{"a":"A.The signal should be repeated five times without any break between the groups ","b":"B.The signals should be repeated six times without any break between the groups ","c":"C.The dots should be made as long as the dashes ","d":"D.The signal should be transmitted at maximum power if possible"}},{"num":9,"sample":"5A39","correct":"B","question":"In case of distress, urgency or safety, the speed of radiotelegraph transmission should not in general exceed: ","answers":{"a":"A.Eleven words per minute ","b":"B.Sixteen words per minute ","c":"C.Twenty words per minute ","d":"D.Twenty-five words per minute"}},{"num":10,"sample":"5A310","correct":"D","question":"In testing a radiotelegraph transmitter the operator generally makes use of the signal: ","answers":{"a":"A.SSS SSS ","b":"B.TTT TTT ","c":"C.QQQ QQQ ","d":"D.VVV VVV"}},{"num":11,"sample":"5A311","correct":"C","question":"If a radiotelegraph station transmits 1  -....-  2, the receiving operator would copy: ","answers":{"a":"A.1, I/2 ","b":"B.I/2 ","c":"C.l l/2 ","d":"D.1 minus 1/2"}},{"num":12,"sample":"5A312","correct":"C","question":"The preamble of a radiotelegram is usually prepared by the: ","answers":{"a":"A.Central accounting office ","b":"B.Office where delivery is made ","c":"C.Office of origin of the message ","d":"D.Person who signs the message"}},{"num":13,"sample":"5A413","correct":"A","question":"A radiotelegram usually consists of: ","answers":{"a":"A.Preamble, address, text and signature ","b":"B.Preamble, text and signature only ","c":"C.Preamble and text only ","d":"D.Check, address and signature only"}},{"num":14,"sample":"5A414","correct":"D","question":"The preamble to a radiotelegram usually contains the: ","answers":{"a":"A.Address for delivery ","b":"B.Signature of sender ","c":"C.Name of the operator on duty ","d":"D.Date of filing"}},{"num":15,"sample":"5A415","correct":"D","question":"The service prefix on a radiotelegram is used to indicate the: ","answers":{"a":"A.Office or origin ","b":"B.Destination of the telegram ","c":"C.Serial number of the telegram ","d":"D.Class of handling or charge rate"}},{"num":16,"sample":"5A416","correct":"B","question":"Word count in a radiotelegram indicates: ","answers":{"a":"A.The charge for each word ","b":"B.The number of chargeable words in the radiotelegram ","c":"C.That the radiotelegram has been paid ","d":"D.That numbers or odd symbols in the telegram have been collated"}},{"num":17,"sample":"5A517","correct":"C","question":"Confidential radiotelegraph messages are often transmitted by means of: ","answers":{"a":"A.Roman numerals ","b":"B.Q code signals only ","c":"C.Cipher or code language ","d":"D.Phillips code"}},{"num":18,"sample":"5A518","correct":"D","question":"Collated words or numbers on a radiotelegram are: ","answers":{"a":"A.All chargeable words in the telegram ","b":"B.Words or numbers sent in groups of five ","c":"C.Long words or numbers broken up into two or more words or units ","d":"D.Words or numbers in the telegram that are restated at the end of the telegram for verification"}},{"num":19,"sample":"5A519","correct":"C","question":"A message requesting or giving information concerning another message is called a: ","answers":{"a":"A.Franked message ","b":"B.Distress message ","c":"C.Service message ","d":"D.Paid deadhead message"}},{"num":20,"sample":"5A520","correct":"A","question":"If a radiotelegraph station receives and transmits messages for the general public: ","answers":{"a":"A.The station must be licensed to handle public correspondence ","b":"B.The chief operator must hold a radiotelegraph first class operator license ","c":"C.The station must be accessible to the general public ","d":"D.The station must be a government station"}},{"num":21,"sample":"5A621","correct":"D","question":"Qsignals are used because they: ","answers":{"a":"A.Convey a secret meaning ","b":"B.Replace the Morse code ","c":"C.May be used in place of assigned call letters ","d":"D.Expedite communications"}},{"num":22,"sample":"5A622","correct":"B","question":"If a station reports that your signal has changed from QSA 1 to QSA 5, you would know that: ","answers":{"a":"A.Your signals are very weak ","b":"B.Your signals are very strong ","c":"C.Your telegraph key needs adjustment ","d":"D.Your signals are transmitted too slow"}},{"num":23,"sample":"5A623","correct":"D","question":"If you are standing by because other stations have been carrying on distress traffic and you hear one of them transmitting a general call followed by QUM, you would know that: ","answers":{"a":"A.There has been great loss of life and property ","b":"B.The distress is becoming more severe ","c":"C.You should transmit QRT ","d":"D.The distress traffic has ended"}},{"num":24,"sample":"5A624","correct":"B","question":"QRL means: ","answers":{"a":"A.Stand by ","b":"B.I am busy ","c":"C.Stop sending ","d":"D.I have nothing for you"}},{"num":25,"sample":"5A725","correct":"C","question":"The proper way for station KABC to call station WDEF is: ","answers":{"a":"A.WDEF VE KABC K ","b":"B.WDEF WDEF K DE KABC KABC K ","c":"C.WDEF WDEF WDEF DE KABC KABC KABC ","d":"D.KABC KABC AR WDEF WDEF K"}},{"num":26,"sample":"5A726","correct":"D","question":"The proper way for station WDEF to answer station KABC is: ","answers":{"a":"A.KABC VAWDEF V ","b":"B.KABC K WDEF K ","c":"C.WDEF WDEF AR KABC KABC ","d":"D.KABC KABC KABC DE WDEF WDEF WDEF K"}},{"num":27,"sample":"5A727","correct":"D","question":"Radio operators listening to CW signals for long periods may get relief from hearing fatigue by: ","answers":{"a":"A.Switching to AVC ","b":"B.Increasing the receiver volume ","c":"C.Using two receivers simultaneously ","d":"D.Changing the tone of the signal"}},{"num":28,"sample":"5A728","correct":"C","question":"The speed of transmission of radiotelegraph signals in routine communications should not exceed: ","answers":{"a":"A.Ten WPM ","b":"B.Twenty WPM ","c":"C.The maximum speed that the receiving operator can receive accurately ","d":"D.Thirty WPM"}},{"num":29,"sample":"5A829","correct":"A","question":"A system of radiotelegraphy in which the receiving operator can press his key and signal the transmitting operator to interrupt his transmission is called: ","answers":{"a":"A.Break-in operation ","b":"B.Reflex operation ","c":"C.Multiplex operation ","d":"D.Simplex operation"}},{"num":30,"sample":"5A830","correct":"B","question":"When receiving CW signals through interference: ","answers":{"a":"A.The crystal filter switch should be off ","b":"B.The crystal filter switch should be on ","c":"C.The receiver must be adjusted for broad tuning ","d":"D.The audio volume control must always be set at maximum"}},{"num":31,"sample":"5A831","correct":"A","question":"If a radio receiver blocks on the reception of strong A2 signals: ","answers":{"a":"A.The RF gain should be reduced ","b":"B.The BFO control should be on ","c":"C.Headphones should be used ","d":"D.The antenna trimmer should be set for maximum signal"}},{"num":32,"sample":"5A832","correct":"D","question":"When receiving type A2 signals on a receiver: ","answers":{"a":"A.The audio volume must be set at maximum ","b":"B.The crystal phasing switch must be on ","c":"C.The antenna aligning control must be adjusted for maximum signal ","d":"D.The BFO is generally turned off"}},{"num":33,"sample":"5A933","correct":"D","question":"In the care of a hand radiotelegraph transmitting key, the operator should occasionally: ","answers":{"a":"A.Wash the key with salt and water ","b":"B.Apply petroleum jelly to the key contacts ","c":"C.Lubricate the key pivots with linseed oil ","d":"D.Clean or burnish the key contacts"}},{"num":34,"sample":"5A934","correct":"D","question":"In addition to distress, safety and urgency signals and messages, the International Distress Frequency is normally used for: ","answers":{"a":"A.Radiotelephone broadcasting at sea ","b":"B.Transmitting public correspondence to aircraft ","c":"C.Time signals ","d":"D.General calling"}},{"num":35,"sample":"5A935","correct":"D","question":"As a general rule, the distress call when sent by radiotelegraphy is preceded by: ","answers":{"a":"A.The operating signal CP ","b":"B.The operating signal CQ ","c":"C.The operating signal QRT ","d":"D.The automatic alarm signal"}},{"num":36,"sample":"5A1036","correct":"C","question":"As a general rule when sending a Distress Call by radiotelegraphy, the Distress Signal and call sign of the station in distress appear: ","answers":{"a":"A.Five times in each call ","b":"B.Eight times in each call ","c":"C.Three times in each call ","d":"D.Seven times in each call"}},{"num":37,"sample":"5A1037","correct":"B","question":"When a station receives no answer to a distress message on the International Distress Frequency it may repeat the message on: ","answers":{"a":"A.A standard broadcast frequency only ","b":"B.Any available frequency ","c":"C.2091 kc only ","d":"D.Coast Guard frequencies only"}},{"num":38,"sample":"5A1038","correct":"D","question":"Greenwich mean time is a: ","answers":{"a":"A.Standard time at any given zone as indicated on clocks with dial marked 0000 to 0600 ","b":"B.Time system used at sea in which time is expressed in bells, as 4 bells, 8 bells, etc. ","c":"C.Time difference between the Greenwich meridian and the international date line expressed from 0000 to 2400 hours ","d":"D.Time at the meridian of Greenwich, England, and reckoned from 0000 to 2400 hours beginning at midnight"}},{"num":39,"sample":"5A1139","correct":"C","question":"The radio silent period of the maritime service beginning at 15 minutes and 45 minutes past the hour on 500 kilocycles is for the purpose of: ","answers":{"a":"A.Receiving time signals ","b":"B.Receiving weather reports ","c":"C.Listening for distress calls ","d":"D.Transmitting ship call letter lists"}},{"num":40,"sample":"5A1140","correct":"D","question":"As a general rule radiotelegrams transmitted by a ship radiotelegraph station are to be numbered in a separate series for the traffic: ","answers":{"a":"A.Each year to each separate land station ","b":"B.Each six months from the mobile station ","c":"C.Each month to each separate land station ","d":"D.Each day to each separate land station"}},{"num":41,"sample":"5A1141","correct":"D","question":"When a station in the maritime mobile service is calling CQ and the call is not followed by K, the transmitted message: ","answers":{"a":"A.Has priority over all other transmissions ","b":"B.Must be considered confidential ","c":"C.Must be transmitted only during silent periods ","d":"D.Is intended for anyone who can intercept it"}},{"num":42,"sample":"5A1242","correct":"A","question":"A land station receiving a distress message must immediately take the necessary action to: ","answers":{"a":"A.Notify the authorities participating in the operation of rescue facilities ","b":"B.Ask the steamship port office for permission to retransmit the distress message, if necessary ","c":"C.Call CQ and give the location of the land station immediately ","d":"D.Retransmit the message without delay"}},{"num":43,"sample":"5A1243","correct":"A","question":"A conventional hand telegraph key is sometimes adjusted for speed by: ","answers":{"a":"A.Adjusting the key spring tension and contacts separation ","b":"B.Adjusting the width of a vibrating arm ","c":"C.Varying the pressure on the key contacts ","d":"D.Adding or removing weights on the key arm"}},{"num":44,"sample":"5A1244","correct":"C","question":"An eligible person may: ","answers":{"a":"A.Hold two unexpired radiotelegraph operator's certificates at the same time ","b":"B.Hold a second class radiotelegraph operator's certificate and a marine radio operator's permit ","c":"C.Hold only one class of valid radiotelegraph operator's certificate ","d":"D.Hold a second class radiotelegraph operator's certificate and a restricted radiotelephone operator's permit"}},{"num":45,"sample":"5A1245","correct":"D","question":"What class of station may not be operated by a third class radiotelegraph permit holder? ","answers":{"a":"A.Television broadcast station ","b":"B.Class 1-b, 2-b, 3-b coast stations ","c":"C.Ship station open to public correspondence by telegraphy ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":46,"sample":"5A1346","correct":"C","question":"Who is not authorized to make technical adjustment to a radiotelephone transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.1st class radiotelephone operator permit holder ","b":"B.2nd class radiotelegraph permit holder ","c":"C.3rd class radiotelegraph holder ","d":"D.General radiotelegraph holder"}},{"num":47,"sample":"5A1347","correct":"D","question":"Who is authorized to make technical adjustments to a radiotelegraph transmitter? ","answers":{"a":"A.1st class radiotelegraph operator permit holder ","b":"B.2nd class radiotelegraph operator permit holder ","c":"C.3rd class radiotelegraph operator permit holder ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":48,"sample":"5A1348","correct":"D","question":"The operator on duty at a manually operated radiotelegraph station normally posts his license or permit: ","answers":{"a":"A.At the place where he is on duty ","b":"B.On his person ","c":"C.Neither A or B ","d":"D.Both A and B"}},{"num":49,"sample":"5A1449","correct":"B","question":"If a radiotelegraph operator makes an error in transmitting message text, he may indicate that an error has been made by sending: ","answers":{"a":"A.Error ","b":"B.A series of 8 or 9 dots ","c":"C.IMI ","d":"D.XXX"}},{"num":50,"sample":"5A1450","correct":"B","question":"What signals are generally transmitted when testing a transmission? ","answers":{"a":"A.A series of 'e's ","b":"B.A series of 'v's ","c":"C.The word 'Test' sent three times ","d":"D.***<This answer left blank by the FCC>"}},{"num":51,"sample":"5A1451","correct":"A","question":"How should fractions be sent in order to avoid confusion? ","answers":{"a":"A.A hyphen or dash is always transmitted between a whole number and a fraction ","b":"B.The numbers should be spelled out ","c":"C.Numbers involving fractions should never be sent ","d":"D.Numbers involving fractions normally are not confused"}},{"num":52,"sample":"5A1552","correct":"D","question":"What does the radiotelegraph message contain in addition to the preamble? ","answers":{"a":"A.Address ","b":"B.Text ","c":"C.Signatures ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":53,"sample":"5A1553","correct":"A","question":"What is a coded designation that appears as a group of letters in the preamble? ","answers":{"a":"A.Service indicator ","b":"B.Ciphers ","c":"C.Handling directions ","d":"D.Signature"}},{"num":54,"sample":"5A1554","correct":"A","question":"Word count or check in a radiotelegraph message usually indicates: ","answers":{"a":"A.The number of words that will be charged ","b":"B.The total number of words in the preamble and text ","c":"C.The total number of words in the text and signature ","d":"D.The total number of words in the preamble, text and signature"}},{"num":55,"sample":"5A1555","correct":"C","question":"What time does the serial numbering of radio message begin? ","answers":{"a":"A.OOOO UTC daily ","b":"B.The period of numbering varies in some foreign stations ","c":"C.Both A & B ","d":"D.1200 UTC daily"}},{"num":56,"sample":"5A1656","correct":"A","question":"Code or cipher groups are often used in radiotelegraph messages for: ","answers":{"a":"A.Security reasons ","b":"B.Abbreviating handling directions ","c":"C.Operating signals ","d":"D.Checking word count"}},{"num":57,"sample":"5A1657","correct":"A","question":"Figures or odd symbles are collected: ","answers":{"a":"A.To make certain of their accuracy ","b":"B.To put them into a more convenient order ","c":"C.To give a correct word count ","d":"D.For security reasons"}},{"num":58,"sample":"5A1658","correct":"C","question":"Figures or odd symbols are ____ to make certain of their accuracy: ","answers":{"a":"A.Counted ","b":"B.Put into a more convenient order ","c":"C.Collected ","d":"D.Sent twice"}},{"num":59,"sample":"5A1659","correct":"A","question":"Receiving conditions are bad.  What operating signal would be used to request each word or group twice? ","answers":{"a":"A.QSZ ","b":"B.QRO ","c":"C.QRK ","d":"D.QRX"}},{"num":60,"sample":"5A1760","correct":"D","question":"A service message refers to: ","answers":{"a":"A.A military message ","b":"B.A message sent by the master of the vessel ","c":"C.A free message ","d":"D.A message handled previously"}},{"num":61,"sample":"5A1761","correct":"D","question":"Why are 'Q' signals used in radiotelegraph communications? ","answers":{"a":"A.They permit a short transmission time in handling of common phrases ","b":"B.To avoid operator fatigue ","c":"C.They are used internationally and overcome language problems ","d":"D.Both A & C"}},{"num":62,"sample":"5A1762","correct":"A","question":"In using 'Q' signals to ask a question, you: ","answers":{"a":"A.Follow the Q signal with a question mark ","b":"B.Prefix the Q signal with a question mark ","c":"C.Send a Q signal twice ","d":"D.Assume the receiving operator knows it as a question"}},{"num":63,"sample":"5A1863","correct":"A","question":"The 'Q' signal for 'The name of my station is...' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.QRA ","b":"B.QRH? ","c":"C.QRI? ","d":"D.QSB"}},{"num":64,"sample":"5A1864","correct":"B","question":"The 'Q' signal for 'Are you being interfered with?...' is? ","answers":{"a":"A.QRM ","b":"B.QRM? ","c":"C.QRN ","d":"D.QRN?"}},{"num":65,"sample":"5A1865","correct":"A","question":"The 'Q' signal for 'I am troubled by static...' is? ","answers":{"a":"A.QRN ","b":"B.QRN? ","c":"C.QRM ","d":"D.QRM?"}},{"num":66,"sample":"5A1866","correct":"C","question":"The 'Q' signal for 'stop sending...' is? ","answers":{"a":"A.QRT? ","b":"B.QRU? ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.QRU"}},{"num":67,"sample":"5A1967","correct":"B","question":"If the signal strength of a radiotelegraph signal is reported on a scale of 1-5, what is the strongest signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.1 ","b":"B.4 ","c":"C.3 ","d":"D.2"}},{"num":68,"sample":"5A1968","correct":"A","question":"If the signal strength of a radiotelegraph signal is reported on a scale of 1-5, what is the weakest signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.1 ","b":"B.4 ","c":"C.3 ","d":"D.2"}},{"num":69,"sample":"5A1969","correct":"B","question":"If you are called by another station, but you are busy with other traffic, what should you do? ","answers":{"a":"A.Acknowledge the call ","b":"B.Acknowledge the call and conclude by indicating a number signifying the number of minutes delay ","c":"C.Acknowledge the call and conclude by a number signifying the order in which the traffic will be answered ","d":"D.Ask the calling station to call back later"}},{"num":70,"sample":"5A1970","correct":"C","question":"If you are called by another station, but you are busy and anticipate a delay in excess of 10 minutes, what should you do? ","answers":{"a":"A.Apologize for the delay ","b":"B.Indicate the reason for the delay ","c":"C.Indicate the reason for the delay and give the number of minutes of delay ","d":"D.Ask the calling station to call back later"}},{"num":71,"sample":"5A2071","correct":"A","question":"The procedure of radiotelegraph transmission in which one station calls another is: ","answers":{"a":"A.WCXY WCXY WCXY DE KMEX KMEX KMEX K ","b":"B.WCXY WCXY DE KMEX K ","c":"C.WCXY WCXY WCXY WCXY WCXY WCXY DE KMEX K ","d":"D.WCXY DE KMEX K"}},{"num":72,"sample":"5A2072","correct":"A","question":"The procedure of radiotelegraph transmission in which one station answers the call of another is...? ","answers":{"a":"A.KMEX KMEX KMEX DE WCXY WCXY WCXY R K ","b":"B.KMEX DE WCXY R ","c":"C.KMEX KMEX KMEX DE WCXY WCXY WCXY RRR ","d":"D.KMEX KMEX DE WCXY IMI"}},{"num":73,"sample":"5A2073","correct":"B","question":"A station that handles paid or toll radio messages for the general public at established rates, is open to: ","answers":{"a":"A.Special messages ","b":"B.Public correspondence ","c":"C.Private correspondence ","d":"D.Both A & C"}},{"num":74,"sample":"5A2074","correct":"B","question":"How should the speed of transmission of radiotelegraph signals be determined? ","answers":{"a":"A.In accordance with the desire of the transmitting operator ","b":"B.In accordance with the desire of the receiving operator ","c":"C.Speed should not exceed 16 wpm ","d":"D.Speed should not exceed 20 wpm"}},{"num":75,"sample":"5A2175","correct":"B","question":"What is the result of a long period of listening to CW telegraph signal of continuous tone? ","answers":{"a":"A.Increased operator response to weak signals ","b":"B.Hearing fatigue of the operator ","c":"C.A peak in hearing a continuous tone ","d":"D.Both A & C"}},{"num":76,"sample":"5A2176","correct":"A","question":"How can an operator relieve hearing fatigue caused by a long period of listening to a CW telegraph signal of constant tone? ","answers":{"a":"A.Vary the frequency of the tones with the BFO control ","b":"B.Vary the volume of the tone ","c":"C.Vary the frequency of the tone by turning to a harmonic of the actual frequency ","d":"D.Both B & C"}},{"num":77,"sample":"5A2177","correct":"A","question":"What is a cause of hearing fatigue? ","answers":{"a":"A.A long period of listening to a CW telegraph signal of continuous tone ","b":"B.A CW telegraph signal with varying tones ","c":"C.A poor radiotelegraph signal ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":78,"sample":"5A2178","correct":"D","question":"What is meant by a break in operation at a radiotelegraph station? ","answers":{"a":"A.When the key is up, the station is capable of receiving a signal ","b":"B.Automatic switching between receiving and transmit modes of the station ","c":"C.Both stations are capable of interrupting each other ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":79,"sample":"5A2279","correct":"B","question":"What kind of operation allows two stations to interrupt each other, informing the sending station immediately when the receiving station has missed a part of the message? ","answers":{"a":"A.Override ","b":"B.Break in ","c":"C.Duplex ","d":"D.Interrupt"}},{"num":80,"sample":"5A2280","correct":"D","question":"In a receiver designed for both radiotelephone and radiotelegraph reception, how should the AVC control be set for reception of CW radiotelegraph signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.It's OFF position ","b":"B.Fast AVC can be used to advantage in the reception of radiotelegraph signals ","c":"C.To it's ON position for slow AVC ","d":"D.Both A & B"}},{"num":81,"sample":"5A2281","correct":"D","question":"In communications receivers, the insertion of a crystal filter: ","answers":{"a":"A.Narrows the receiving band width ","b":"B.Minimizes interference from stations operating on nearby frequencies ","c":"C.Reduces the interference of static ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":82,"sample":"5A2382","correct":"C","question":"Interference from stations operating on nearby frequencies can be minimized by: ","answers":{"a":"A.Using a crystal filter ","b":"B.Tuning the desired frequency very carefully ","c":"C.Combining A & B ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":83,"sample":"5A2383","correct":"A","question":"If a radiotelegraph receiver blocks on the reception of strong signals, what correction can be made? ","answers":{"a":"A.Reduce the radio frequency gain control ","b":"B.Increase the radio frequency gain control ","c":"C.Disable the squelch control ","d":"D.Disconnect the antenna"}},{"num":84,"sample":"5A2384","correct":"A","question":"How would you adjust a radiotelegraph receiver from the transmission of A2 emissions? ","answers":{"a":"A.Turn off the BFO and adjust the receiver from the reception of the tone-modulated signal ","b":"B.Employ the slit frequency divider ","c":"C.Both A & B ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":85,"sample":"5A2485","correct":"C","question":"If a radiotelegraph transmitting station can be heard at more than one place on the tuning dial of the receiver: ","answers":{"a":"A.The station is transmitting on more than one frequency ","b":"B.The station is transmitting on odd harmonics ","c":"C.The receiver is being tuned to an image frequency ","d":"D.Both B & C"}},{"num":86,"sample":"5A2486","correct":"D","question":"Sometimes a radiotelegraph transmitting station can be heard at more than one place on the tuning dial of the receiver.  What does this indicate? ","answers":{"a":"A.It is always an indication that the station is transmitting on more than one frequency ","b":"B.That the receiver is being tuned to an image frequency ","c":"C.The image frequency signal will be weaker than the signal level received when the receiver is set to the proper frequency of the transmitting station ","d":"D.Both B & C"}},{"num":87,"sample":"5A2487","correct":"D","question":"What is an indicator that the receiver is being tuned to an image frequency? ","answers":{"a":"A.Hearing a given radiotelegraph transmitting station at more than one place on the tuning dial of the receiver ","b":"B.The image frequency signal will be weaker than the signal level received when the receiver is set to the proper frequency of the transmitting station ","c":"C.The station is transmitting on more than one frequency ","d":"D.Both A & B"}},{"num":88,"sample":"5A2588","correct":"A","question":"The contact opening of a radiotelegraph transmitting relay should be usually adjusted for about: ","answers":{"a":"A.1/16 inch ","b":"B.1/8 inch ","c":"C.1/32 inch ","d":"D.1/4 inch"}},{"num":89,"sample":"5A2589","correct":"B","question":"The contact opening of a manual radiotelegraph transmitting relay should be: ","answers":{"a":"A.Always the same for slow as it is for high speed ","b":"B.Less for high speed operation ","c":"C.More for high speed operation ","d":"D.Both B & C"}},{"num":90,"sample":"5A2590","correct":"C","question":"Side adjustments of a manual radiotelegraph transmitting relay: ","answers":{"a":"A.Permit proper alignment ","b":"B.Permit free vertical movement of the arm ","c":"C.Both A & B ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":91,"sample":"5A2691","correct":"A","question":"Proper alignment and free vertical movement of the arm of a manual radiotelegraph transmitting relay are accomplished by: ","answers":{"a":"A.Side adjustments ","b":"B.1/4 inch contact openings ","c":"C.Both A & B ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":92,"sample":"5A2692","correct":"C","question":"To adjust a manual radiotelegraph transmitting relay for high speed: ","answers":{"a":"A.Loosen the spring tension ","b":"B.Tighten the spring tension ","c":"C.Adjust the spring tension to the individual's comfort requirements ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":93,"sample":"5A2693","correct":"D","question":"With a 'bug': ","answers":{"a":"A.Dashes are made manually ","b":"B.The dot speed is set by weights on the arm of the 'bug' ","c":"C.Dot-contact speed of usually about 1/8 inch is used ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":94,"sample":"5A2794","correct":"A","question":"Spring tension of a properly adjusted 'bug': ","answers":{"a":"A.Is such that 12 to 30 clear dots are sent continuously when the dot lever is held on the keying position ","b":"B.Is such that 20 or more clear dots are sent continuously when the dot lever is held on the keying position ","c":"C.Is such that 10 or more clear dots are sent continuously when the dot lever is held on the keying position ","d":"D.Has nothing to do with the dots"}},{"num":95,"sample":"5A2795","correct":"C","question":"With a 'bug': ","answers":{"a":"A.Dots are made manually ","b":"B.The dash speed is set by weights on the arm of the 'bug' ","c":"C.Contact spacing of the dash arm is set between 1/32 and 1/16 inch ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":96,"sample":"5A2796","correct":"D","question":"An automatic key or 'bug' should be properly adjusted to send good readable radiotelegraph signals.  The dash arm should be adjusted for: ","answers":{"a":"A.Proper alignment ","b":"B.Required spacing ","c":"C.Proper spring tension ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":97,"sample":"5A2897","correct":"A","question":"The bearing supporting the vertical shaft on which the dot-dash levers are suspended on an automatic key (or bug) should be adjusted up or down until the movable dot contact on the vibrator arm: ","answers":{"a":"A.Makes accurate full-face contact with the stationary dot contact on the post ","b":"B.Makes partial contact with the stationary dot contact on the post ","c":"C.Makes no contact with the stationary dot contact on the post ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":98,"sample":"5A2898","correct":"C","question":"The bearing adjustment screws of an automatic key (or bug) should be set: ","answers":{"a":"A.So that lateral motion of the dot and dash levers are free ","b":"B.So that there is no end play of the levers ","c":"C.Both A & B ","d":"D.Neither A or B"}},{"num":99,"sample":"5A2899","correct":"A","question":"The movable dash contact on the dash lever of an automatic key (or bug) should be adjusted: ","answers":{"a":"A.So that it makes full-face contact with the stationary dash contact on the post ","b":"B.So that it makes partial contact with the stationary dash contact on the post ","c":"C.So that it makes no contact with the stationary dash contact on the post ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":100,"sample":"5A29100","correct":"A","question":"The movable dash contact on the dash lever should be adjusted so that it makes full-face contact with the stationary dash contact on the post.  It should then: ","answers":{"a":"A.Be locked primarily in that position ","b":"B.Not be locked in that position ","c":"C.Be readjusted for partial contact ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":101,"sample":"5A29101","correct":"C","question":"The spacing of the stationary dash contact of an automatic key (or bug) should: ","answers":{"a":"A.Be adjusted to about 1/16 to 1/32 of an inch ","b":"B.Be adjusted to suit the sending style of the operator ","c":"C.Both A & B ","d":"D.Neither A or B"}},{"num":102,"sample":"5A29102","correct":"A","question":"The adjustment of the dot lever travel should be: ","answers":{"a":"A.1/16 to 3/16 inch ","b":"B.1/8 to 1/4 inch ","c":"C.1/32 to 1/8 inch ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":103,"sample":"5A30103","correct":"A","question":"In an automatic key (or bug), spacing of the stationary dot contact ___ so that when the dot lever is pressed and held over should be adjusted: ","answers":{"a":"A.So the instrument will make 12 to 30 clear dots ","b":"B.So that more that 30 clear dots will be made ","c":"C.So that less that 5 clear dots will be made ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":104,"sample":"5A30104","correct":"D","question":"The dot speed adjustment weight of an automatic key (or bug) should be set: ","answers":{"a":"A.So that the instrument makes dots at a speed proportioned to the speed at which the operator normally makes dashes ","b":"B.So that about 3 dots are made in the same time the operator makes one dash ","c":"C.So that for practical operating speeds from 20 to 40 wpm, there will be a dot speed of from 8 to 16 dots per second ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":105,"sample":"5A30105","correct":"A","question":"The dot speed adjustment weight of an automatic key (or bug) should be set: ","answers":{"a":"A.So that the practical operating speeds from 20 to 40 wpm, there will be a dot speed of from 8 to 16 dots per second ","b":"B.So that for practical operating speeds from 10 to 20 wpm, there will be a dot speed of from 16 to 30 dots per second ","c":"C.So that for practical operating speed of 16 wpm, there will be a dot speed of 16 dots per second ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":106,"sample":"5A31106","correct":"A","question":"Sometimes misalignment of a receiver will cause an unwanted signal to get through to the first detector causing an intermediate frequency signal which passes through the receiver normally.  Such a signal is called: ","answers":{"a":"A.Image interference ","b":"B.Intermediate frequency interference ","c":"C.Mixer interference ","d":"D.Heterodyne"}},{"num":107,"sample":"5A31107","correct":"D","question":"To obtain maximum response to weak signals in a super-heterodyne receiver: ","answers":{"a":"A.R-F gain control should be fully advanced ","b":"B.BFO control varied for the clearest tone ","c":"C.ABC switched off ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":108,"sample":"5A31108","correct":"D","question":"How should a superheterodyne receiver be adjusted for a maximum response to strong CW signals? ","answers":{"a":"A.Automatic volume control may be left on ","b":"B.R-F gain control should be somewhat reduced ","c":"C.The BFO should be varied for the desired output frequency ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":109,"sample":"5A32109","correct":"D","question":"A system whereby the receiving operator may interrupt the transmitting operator at any point is: ","answers":{"a":"A.A break in operation ","b":"B.Accomplished with a relay which changes the antenna from receiving to transmitting ","c":"C.Ineffective in general practice ","d":"D.Both A & B"}},{"num":110,"sample":"5A32110","correct":"A","question":"A station which handles toll messages is a station: ","answers":{"a":"A.Open to public services ","b":"B.That carries non-public communication for business ","c":"C.In the highway trucking business ","d":"D.For inter-city ____"}},{"num":111,"sample":"5A32111","correct":"C","question":"A code designation made up from 2 to 4 letters as the first part of the preamble of a radiotelegraph message: ","answers":{"a":"A.Is a 'Service prefix' ","b":"B.Is an 'Indicator' ","c":"C.Both A & B ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":112,"sample":"5A33112","correct":"B","question":"A service prefix of a radiotelegraph message: ","answers":{"a":"A.Indicates which branch of service the message originated in ","b":"B.Contains direction for handling ","c":"C.Tells the operator how fast to send the message ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":113,"sample":"5A33113","correct":"A","question":"A service prefix of a radiotelegraph message may also be known as: ","answers":{"a":"A.An indicator ","b":"B.The preamble ","c":"C.A code designator ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":114,"sample":"5A33114","correct":"A","question":"An indicator of the radiotelegraph message may also be known as: ","answers":{"a":"A.A service prefix ","b":"B.The preamble ","c":"C.A code designator ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":115,"sample":"5B1115","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation requesting a repetition of all sent before a specific word is: ","answers":{"a":"A.?AB ","b":"B.CQ ","c":"C.IMI ","d":"D.C?"}},{"num":116,"sample":"5B1116","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'I repeat the figures' in abbreviation form is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AA ","b":"B.ABV ","c":"C.ADS ","d":"D.BF"}},{"num":117,"sample":"5B1117","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for repetition of an address is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AA ","b":"B.AB ","c":"C.AR ","d":"D.?ADS"}},{"num":118,"sample":"5B1118","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'end of transmission' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AA ","b":"B.AR ","c":"C.K ","d":"D.C"}},{"num":119,"sample":"5B1119","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'waiting period' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AA ","b":"B.BQ ","c":"C.AS ","d":"D.CS"}},{"num":120,"sample":"5B1120","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation requesting a repetition of all sent after a specific word is: ","answers":{"a":"A.?AA ","b":"B.ABV ","c":"C.AA? ","d":"D.DB"}},{"num":121,"sample":"5B1121","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used to interrupt a transmission in progress is: ","answers":{"a":"A.BN ","b":"B.BT ","c":"C.BF ","d":"D.BQ"}},{"num":122,"sample":"5B1122","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used to request a repetition of all between - and - is: ","answers":{"a":"A.?BN ","b":"B.BF ","c":"C.BN? ","d":"D.BQ"}},{"num":123,"sample":"5B1123","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used to reply to and RQ (indication of a request) is: ","answers":{"a":"A.BF ","b":"B.C ","c":"C.BQ ","d":"D.CFM"}},{"num":124,"sample":"5B1124","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used for 'yes' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.IMI ","b":"B.BQ ","c":"C.CS ","d":"D.C"}},{"num":125,"sample":"5B1125","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used for 'I confirm' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.COL ","b":"B.CFM ","c":"C.CL ","d":"D.CS"}},{"num":126,"sample":"5B1126","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used for 'I am closing my station' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.COL ","b":"B.CL ","c":"C.CS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":127,"sample":"5B2127","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Collate' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.CL ","b":"B.CS ","c":"C.CFM ","d":"D.COL"}},{"num":128,"sample":"5B2128","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for a general call to two or more specific stations is: ","answers":{"a":"A.CQ ","b":"B.CP ","c":"C.CS ","d":"D.C"}},{"num":129,"sample":"5B2129","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for a general call to all stations is: ","answers":{"a":"A.CQ ","b":"B.CP ","c":"C.CS ","d":"D.C"}},{"num":130,"sample":"5B2130","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used to request a call sign is: ","answers":{"a":"A.C ","b":"B.BF ","c":"C.CS ","d":"D.B"}},{"num":131,"sample":"5B2131","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'I cannot give you a bearing; you are not in the calibrated sector of the station' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DC ","b":"B.DF ","c":"C.CS ","d":"D.DB"}},{"num":132,"sample":"5B2132","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'The minimum of your signal suitable for the bearing ' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DF ","b":"B.DC ","c":"C.DG ","d":"D.DI"}},{"num":133,"sample":"5B2133","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Your bearings at <time> was ___ degrees, in the doubtful sector of this section, with a possible error of ___ degrees' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DI ","b":"B.DG ","c":"C.DC ","d":"D.DF"}},{"num":134,"sample":"5B2134","correct":"C","question":"In radiotelegraphy the general call to all stations is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AR ","b":"B.BK ","c":"C.CQ ","d":"D.TU"}},{"num":135,"sample":"5B2135","correct":"D","question":"A signal which means 'received' in radiotelegraph communications is: ","answers":{"a":"A.K ","b":"B.N ","c":"C.C ","d":"D.R"}},{"num":136,"sample":"5B2136","correct":"D","question":"A signal which means 'wait' in radiotelegraph communications is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DE ","b":"B.CP ","c":"C.BT ","d":"D.AS"}},{"num":137,"sample":"5B2137","correct":"D","question":"An operating signal used to mean 'repeat' in radiotelegraph communications is: ","answers":{"a":"A.BT ","b":"B.GR ","c":"C.QUM ","d":"D.RPT"}},{"num":138,"sample":"5B2138","correct":"B","question":"If a called radiotelegraph station is busy, the calling station may be advised to anticipate a return call by sending: ","answers":{"a":"A.QUM ","b":"B.QRX ","c":"C.QSA ","d":"D.QRA"}},{"num":139,"sample":"5B3139","correct":"D","question":"QRZ? means: ","answers":{"a":"A.I am busy ","b":"B.Stop sending ","c":"C.What is the strength of my signals ","d":"D.Who is calling me"}},{"num":140,"sample":"5B3140","correct":"A","question":"What is the radio distress signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.Three dots, three dashes and three dots continuously ","b":"B.XXX ","c":"C.TTT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":141,"sample":"5B3141","correct":"B","question":"What is the radiotelegraph urgency signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.Three dots, three dashes and three dots continuously ","b":"B.XXX ","c":"C.TTT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":142,"sample":"5B3142","correct":"C","question":"What is the radiotelegraph safety signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.Three dots, three dashes and three dots continuously ","b":"B.XXX ","c":"C.TTT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":143,"sample":"5B3143","correct":"A","question":"What speed of radiotelegraph code transmission must not, in general, be exceeded in cases of distress, urgency or safety? ","answers":{"a":"A.16 wpm ","b":"B.20 wpm ","c":"C.13 wpm ","d":"D.18 wpm"}},{"num":144,"sample":"5B3144","correct":"A","question":"What radiotelegraph signal is generally used to call all stations? ","answers":{"a":"A.CQ ","b":"B.BT ","c":"C.AR ","d":"D.IMI"}},{"num":145,"sample":"5B3145","correct":"C","question":"What is the radiotelegraph signal for 'Waiting'? ","answers":{"a":"A.CQ ","b":"B.BT ","c":"C.AS ","d":"D.IMI"}},{"num":146,"sample":"5B3146","correct":"A","question":"What is the radiotelegraph signal for 'received'? ","answers":{"a":"A.R ","b":"B.K ","c":"C.BT ","d":"D.DE"}},{"num":147,"sample":"5B3147","correct":"D","question":"What is the radiotelegraph signal for 'YES'? ","answers":{"a":"A.BT ","b":"B.IMI ","c":"C.VA ","d":"D.C"}},{"num":148,"sample":"5B4148","correct":"A","question":"What is the radiotelegraph signal for '?'? ","answers":{"a":"A.IMI ","b":"B.C ","c":"C.DE ","d":"D.K"}},{"num":149,"sample":"5B4149","correct":"A","question":"What is the radiotelegraph signal for 'Invitation'? ","answers":{"a":"A.K ","b":"B.C ","c":"C.R ","d":"D.VA"}},{"num":150,"sample":"5B4150","correct":"A","question":"What is the radiotelegraph signal for 'End of Work' sent as a continuous signal? ","answers":{"a":"A.VA ","b":"B.AR ","c":"C.BT ","d":"D.AS"}},{"num":151,"sample":"5B4151","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Please advise me if you note an error in the bearing given' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DI ","b":"B.DC ","c":"C.DG ","d":"D.DF"}},{"num":152,"sample":"5B4152","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Bearing doubtful in consequence of the bad quality of your signal' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DI ","b":"B.DG ","c":"C.DF ","d":"D.DC"}},{"num":153,"sample":"5B4153","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Bearing doubtful because of interference' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DI ","b":"B.DO ","c":"C.DJ ","d":"D.DP"}},{"num":154,"sample":"5B4154","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Bearing doubtful' as on 'for another bearing later' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DT ","b":"B.DO ","c":"C.DF ","d":"D.DX"}},{"num":155,"sample":"5B4155","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Possible error of bearing may amount to ____ degrees' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DI ","b":"B.DE ","c":"C.DP ","d":"D.DJ"}},{"num":156,"sample":"5B4156","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Adjust your transmitter, the minimum of you signal is too broad' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DJ ","b":"B.DS ","c":"C.DX ","d":"D.DB"}},{"num":157,"sample":"5B5157","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'I cannot furnish you with a bearing; the minimum of you signal is too broad' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DS ","b":"B.DP ","c":"C.DT ","d":"D.DY"}},{"num":158,"sample":"5B5158","correct":"B","question":"The abbreviation for 'Your bearing is reciprocal, (to be used only by the control station of a group of direction-finding when it is addressing stations of the same group)' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DI ","b":"B.DZ ","c":"C.DO ","d":"D.DE"}},{"num":159,"sample":"5B5159","correct":"D","question":"The abbreviation used to separate the call sign of the station called from the call sign of the calling station is: ","answers":{"a":"A.DI ","b":"B.DO ","c":"C.DT ","d":"D.DE"}},{"num":160,"sample":"5B5160","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Here' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.ER ","b":"B.DE ","c":"C.DT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":161,"sample":"5B5161","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Estimated time of arrival' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.ER ","b":"B.ETA ","c":"C.ETI ","d":"D.EXT"}},{"num":162,"sample":"5B5162","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'The punctuation counts' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.ITP ","b":"B.DZ ","c":"C.NIL ","d":"D.K"}},{"num":163,"sample":"5B5163","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Make a series of dashes if I may transmit, make a series of dots to stop my transmission' (not to be used on 500 kHz except in cases of distress) is: ","answers":{"a":"A.K ","b":"B.DT ","c":"C.JM ","d":"D.P"}},{"num":164,"sample":"5B5164","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Invitation to transmit' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.K ","b":"B.DE ","c":"C.TU ","d":"D.W"}},{"num":165,"sample":"5B5165","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for a prefix indicating a message to or from the master of a ship concerning it's operation or navigation is: ","answers":{"a":"A.PBL ","b":"B.MSG ","c":"C.RPT ","d":"D.SIG"}},{"num":166,"sample":"5B5166","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'No' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.N ","b":"B.C ","c":"C.K ","d":"D.P"}},{"num":167,"sample":"5B6167","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'I have nothing to send to you' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.NW ","b":"B.OK ","c":"C.NIL ","d":"D.P"}},{"num":168,"sample":"5B6168","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Now' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.MN ","b":"B.NW ","c":"C.P ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":169,"sample":"5B6169","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'We agree (or it is correct)' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.PBL ","b":"B.P ","c":"C.PTR ","d":"D.R"}},{"num":170,"sample":"5B6170","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Preamble' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.PBL ","b":"B.P ","c":"C.PTR ","d":"D.R"}},{"num":171,"sample":"5B6171","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used by a coast station to request the position and next port of call of a mobile station is: ","answers":{"a":"A.P ","b":"B.PTR ","c":"C.PBL ","d":"D.K"}},{"num":172,"sample":"5B6172","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Received' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.R ","b":"B.K ","c":"C.W ","d":"D.Ok"}},{"num":173,"sample":"5B6173","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Refer to ___' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.RPT ","b":"B.REF ","c":"C.RQ ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":174,"sample":"5B6174","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'I repeated or Repeat' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.REF ","b":"B.RPT ","c":"C.RQ ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":175,"sample":"5B6175","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Indication of a request' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.RPT ","b":"B.RQ ","c":"C.REF ","d":"D.R"}},{"num":176,"sample":"5B6176","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Signature' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.SVC ","b":"B.SIG ","c":"C.SOS ","d":"D.SS"}},{"num":177,"sample":"5B7177","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for requesting a repetition of a signature is: ","answers":{"a":"A.SVC ","b":"B.?SIG ","c":"C.SIG ","d":"D.SS"}},{"num":178,"sample":"5B7178","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation signal for 'Distress' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.SS ","b":"B.SOS ","c":"C.SOS, to be sent as one signal ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":179,"sample":"5B7179","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Indicator preceding the name of a ship station' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.SSS ","b":"B.SYC ","c":"C.SVC ","d":"D.SS"}},{"num":180,"sample":"5B7180","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Prefix indicating a service telegram' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.SYS ","b":"B.SVC ","c":"C.SS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":181,"sample":"5B7181","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Refer to your service telegram' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.SYS ","b":"B.SYC ","c":"C.SS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":182,"sample":"5B7182","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Traffic' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.TR ","b":"B.TFC ","c":"C.TTT ","d":"D.TU"}},{"num":183,"sample":"5B7183","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used as a prefix to indicate reply to PTR is: ","answers":{"a":"A.TTT ","b":"B.TU ","c":"C.TR ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":184,"sample":"5B7184","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation which constitutes the safety signal when sent three times is: ","answers":{"a":"A.TXT ","b":"B.TU ","c":"C.TTT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":185,"sample":"5B7185","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Thank You' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.TFC ","b":"B.TU ","c":"C.TR ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":186,"sample":"5B7186","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Text' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.TXT ","b":"B.TFC ","c":"C.TT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":187,"sample":"5B8187","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation to request a repetition of a 'Text' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.?TXT ","b":"B.TXT ","c":"C.TFC ","d":"D.TT"}},{"num":188,"sample":"5B8188","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'End of work' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.VA ","b":"B.XXX ","c":"C.TTT ","d":"D.KKK"}},{"num":189,"sample":"5B8189","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Word(s)' or 'group(s)' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.K ","b":"B.W ","c":"C.WA ","d":"D.WB"}},{"num":190,"sample":"5B8190","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Word after ___' is/: ","answers":{"a":"A.WA ","b":"B.?WA ","c":"C.WB ","d":"D.?WB"}},{"num":191,"sample":"5B8191","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation requesting a repetition of 'Word after' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.WA ","b":"B.?WA ","c":"C.WB ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":192,"sample":"5B8192","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for ' Word before ___' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.?WB ","b":"B.WB ","c":"C.Either A or B ","d":"D.Neither A or B"}},{"num":193,"sample":"5B8193","correct":"C","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation requesting a repetition of 'Word before ___' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AB ","b":"B.K ","c":"C.?WB ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":194,"sample":"5B8194","correct":"C","question":"This radiotelegraph abbreviation sent three times constitutes the urgency signal: ","answers":{"a":"A.SOS ","b":"B.TTT ","c":"C.XXX ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":195,"sample":"5B8195","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'All sent before a specific word' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AA ","b":"B.AB ","c":"C.AR ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":196,"sample":"5B8196","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for all sent after a specific word is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AA ","b":"B.AB ","c":"C.AR ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":197,"sample":"5B9197","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'Address' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.AD ","b":"B.ADS ","c":"C.AA ","d":"D.AS"}},{"num":198,"sample":"5B9198","correct":"B","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation for 'All between ____ and ____' is: ","answers":{"a":"A.BC ","b":"B.AB ","c":"C.BN ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":199,"sample":"5B9199","correct":"A","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation used after a question mark usually is: ","answers":{"a":"A.A request for a repetition ","b":"B.A questionable procedure ","c":"C.The abbreviation of a statement ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":200,"sample":"5B9200","correct":"D","question":"Cipher language is composed of ____ of no apparent meaning. ","answers":{"a":"A.Words ","b":"B.Names ","c":"C.Combination of letters ","d":"D.All of the above"}},{"num":201,"sample":"5B9201","correct":"D","question":"The radiotelegraph abbreviation with no question mark is: ","answers":{"a":"A.A statement ","b":"B.A questionable procedure ","c":"C.Never used ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":202,"sample":"5B9202","correct":"B","question":"To make a radiotelegraph abbreviation a question: ","answers":{"a":"A.Follow it with a question mark ","b":"B.Proceed it with a question mark ","c":"C.Use no question mark ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":203,"sample":"5B9203","correct":"C","question":"To make a radiotelegraph abbreviation a statement: ","answers":{"a":"A.Follow it with a question mark ","b":"B.Proceed it with a question mark ","c":"C.Use no question mark ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":204,"sample":"5B9204","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'How far approximately are you from my station?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRN ","b":"B.QRB ","c":"C.QRX ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":205,"sample":"5B9205","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'By what private enterprise (or state administration) are the accounts for changes for your station settled?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRT ","b":"B.QRN ","c":"C.QRC ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":206,"sample":"5B9206","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Where are you bound and where are you from?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRL ","b":"B.QRO ","c":"C.QRD ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":207,"sample":"5B10207","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is your ETA at ____?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRE ","b":"B.QRD ","c":"C.QRF ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":208,"sample":"5B10208","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Are you returning to ____?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRL ","b":"B.QRF ","c":"C.QRK ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":209,"sample":"5B10209","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you tell me my exact frequency?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRO ","b":"B.QST ","c":"C.QRG ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":210,"sample":"5B10210","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Does my frequency vary?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRV ","b":"B.QRH ","c":"C.QRC ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":211,"sample":"5B10211","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'How is the tone of my transmission?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRI ","b":"B.QRL ","c":"C.QSV ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":212,"sample":"5B10212","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is the readability of my signals?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRT ","b":"B.QXB ","c":"C.QRK ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":213,"sample":"5B10213","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I increase power?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QST ","b":"B.QRT ","c":"C.QRD ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":214,"sample":"5B10214","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I decrease power?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRQ ","b":"B.QRP ","c":"C.QRV ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":215,"sample":"5B10215","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I send faster?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRQ ","b":"B.QRP ","c":"C.QRS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":216,"sample":"5B10216","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Are you ready for automatic operation?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRQ ","b":"B.QRR ","c":"C.QRS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":217,"sample":"5B11217","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I send more slowly?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRT ","b":"B.QST ","c":"C.QRS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":218,"sample":"5B11218","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have you anything for me?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSO ","b":"B.QRT ","c":"C.QRU ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":219,"sample":"5B11219","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Are you ready?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRU ","b":"B.QRV ","c":"C.QUM ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":220,"sample":"5B11220","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I inform ____ that you are calling him on ____ kHz?' (or MHz) ","answers":{"a":"A.QRW ","b":"B.QRV ","c":"C.QST ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":221,"sample":"5B11221","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'When will you call me again?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QXV ","b":"B.QRT ","c":"C.QRX ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":222,"sample":"5B11222","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is the strength of my signals?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSA ","b":"B.QSD ","c":"C.QSC ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":223,"sample":"5B11223","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Are my signals fading?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSB ","b":"B.QRT ","c":"C.QSL ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":224,"sample":"5B11224","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask ' Are you a cargo vessel?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRT ","b":"B.QSC ","c":"C.QRM ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":225,"sample":"5B11225","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Is my keying defective ?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRN ","b":"B.QST ","c":"C.QSD ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":226,"sample":"5B11226","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is the charge to be collected per word to ____ including your internal telegraph charge?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRL ","b":"B.QSJ ","c":"C.QRA ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":227,"sample":"5B12227","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Can you hear me between your signals?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSK ","b":"B.QRM ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":228,"sample":"5B12228","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Can you acknowledge receipt?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QST ","b":"B.QSL ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":229,"sample":"5B12229","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I repeat the last telegram which I sent you, or some previous telegram?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSL ","b":"B.QRM ","c":"C.QSM ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":230,"sample":"5B12230","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Did you hear me [or...{call sign}] on ____ kHz {MHz}?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSM ","b":"B.QSN ","c":"C.QSO ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":231,"sample":"5B12231","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Can you communicate with ____ direct or by relay?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSL ","b":"B.QSO ","c":"C.QSM ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":232,"sample":"5B12232","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you relay to ____ free of charge?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSP ","b":"B.QRM ","c":"C.QRN ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":233,"sample":"5B12233","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have you a doctor on board {or ... Is (name of person) on board}?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QST ","b":"B.QSQ ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":234,"sample":"5B12234","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I send or reply on this frequency {or on ___ kHz (or MHz)} with emissions of class ___?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUL ","b":"B.QSU ","c":"C.QST ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":235,"sample":"5B12235","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you send on this frequency {or ___ kHz (or MHz)} with emissions of class ___?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSW ","b":"B.QRL ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":236,"sample":"5B12236","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you listen to ___ {call sign(s)} on ___ kHz (or MHz)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUM ","b":"B.QSX ","c":"C.QTB ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":237,"sample":"5B13237","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I change to transmission on another frequency?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSV ","b":"B.QST ","c":"C.QSY ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":238,"sample":"5B13238","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I send each word or group more than once?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSZ ","b":"B.QRM ","c":"C.QSL ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":239,"sample":"5B13239","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I cancel telegram number ____ as if it had not been sent?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTA ","b":"B.QTB ","c":"C.QTC ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":240,"sample":"5B13240","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Do you agree with my counting of words?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTB ","b":"B.QRS ","c":"C.QRB ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":241,"sample":"5B13241","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'How many telegrams have you to send?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QLT ","b":"B.QTC ","c":"C.QST ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":242,"sample":"5B13242","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is my true bearing from you?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRZ ","b":"B.QSM ","c":"C.QTE ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":243,"sample":"5B13243","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you give me the position of my station according to the bearings taken by the direction-finding stations which you control?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSL ","b":"B.QQQ ","c":"C.QTF ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":244,"sample":"5B13244","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you send two dashes of 10 seconds each followed by your call sign (repeat ___ times) {on ___ kHz (or MHz)}?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSL ","b":"B.QSV ","c":"C.QTG ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":245,"sample":"5B13245","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is your position in latitude and longitude (or according to any other indications)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTG ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QST ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":246,"sample":"5B13246","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is your true track?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTI ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QLM ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":247,"sample":"5B14247","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is your speed?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QQQ ","b":"B.QTJ ","c":"C.QTH ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":248,"sample":"5B14248","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is the speed of your aircraft in relation to the surface of the earth?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTH ","b":"B.QTK ","c":"C.QRZ ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":249,"sample":"5B14249","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is your true heading?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRM ","b":"B.QTL ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":250,"sample":"5B14250","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'At what time did you depart from ____ (place)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTN ","b":"B.QSV ","c":"C.QRZ ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":251,"sample":"5B14251","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have you left dock (or port)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSV ","b":"B.QRT ","c":"C.QTO ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":252,"sample":"5B14252","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Are you going to enter dock (or port)' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTP ","b":"B.QRM ","c":"C.QTH ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":253,"sample":"5B14253","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Can you communicate with my station by means of the International Code of Signals?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSV ","b":"B.QTQ ","c":"C.QRP ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":254,"sample":"5B14254","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is the correct time?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRS ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QTR ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":255,"sample":"5B14255","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you send your call sign for ___ minutes...so that your frequency may be measured?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRZ ","b":"B.QTS ","c":"C.QUM ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":256,"sample":"5B14256","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What are the hours during which your station is open?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTV ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QSL ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":257,"sample":"5B15257","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I stand guard for you on the frequency of ____ kHz (or MHz) from ____ to ____ hours?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTV ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QSL ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":258,"sample":"5B15258","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you keep your station open for further communication with me until further notice?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSV ","b":"B.QTX ","c":"C.QRZ ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":259,"sample":"5B15259","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have you news of ____ (call sign)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRZ ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QUA ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":260,"sample":"5B15260","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Can you give me,in the following order, information concerning: visibility, length of clouds, direction and velocity of ground wind at ____ (place of observation)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUB ","b":"B.QSV ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":261,"sample":"5B15261","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is the number of the last message you received from me?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUM ","b":"B.QUC ","c":"C.QQQ ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":262,"sample":"5B15262","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have you received the urgency signal sent by ____ (call sign)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUD ","b":"B.QSZ ","c":"C.QRV ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":263,"sample":"5B15263","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have you received a distress signal sent by ____ (call sign)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QLV ","b":"B.QRL ","c":"C.QUF ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":264,"sample":"5B15264","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you be forced to land?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRL ","b":"B.QUG ","c":"C.QSV ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":265,"sample":"5B15265","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you give me the present barometer pressure at sea level?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUH ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QSH ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":266,"sample":"5B15266","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Are your navigation lights working?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRM ","b":"B.QRV ","c":"C.QUI ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":267,"sample":"5B16267","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you indicate the true course for me to steer toward you with no wind?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUJ ","b":"B.QRK ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":268,"sample":"5B16268","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Can you tell me the condition of the sea observed at ____ (please)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTV ","b":"B.QUK ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":269,"sample":"5B16269","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Can you tell me the swell observed at ____ (please)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUL ","b":"B.QRS ","c":"C.QST ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":270,"sample":"5B16270","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will vessels in my immediate vicinity please indicate their position, true course and speed?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUB ","b":"B.QUN ","c":"C.QRV ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":271,"sample":"5B16271","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I search for (1. Aircraft; 2. Ship; 3. a survival craft;) in the vicinity of ____ latitude ____ longitude?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRZ ","b":"B.QRT ","c":"C.QUO ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":272,"sample":"5B16272","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you indicate your position by (1. Searchlights; 2. Black smoke trail; 3. Pyrotechnic lights)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUP ","b":"B.QSO ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":273,"sample":"5B16273","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I train my searchlights nearby vertical on a cloud... deflect the beam up wind and on the water to facilitate your landing?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUQ ","b":"B.QRZ ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.QSO"}},{"num":274,"sample":"5B16274","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have survivors (1. received survival equipment; 2. been picked up by rescue vessel; 3. been reached by ground rescue party)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QSO ","b":"B.QUR ","c":"C.QRZ ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":275,"sample":"5B16275","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Have you sighted survivors or wreckage?  If so, in what position?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRZ ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QUS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":276,"sample":"5B16276","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Is position of incident marked?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QUT ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QRP ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":277,"sample":"5B17277","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Shall I Home ship or aircraft to my position?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTH ","b":"B.QUU ","c":"C.QLS ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":278,"sample":"5B17278","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is my magnetic bearing from you?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTH ","b":"B.QSL ","c":"C.QUV ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":279,"sample":"5B17279","correct":"B","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'Will you indicate the magnetic course for me to steer towards you with no wind?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QTH ","b":"B.QUX ","c":"C.QSO ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":280,"sample":"5B17280","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is my true bearing from ____ (call sign)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRZ ","b":"B.QSM ","c":"C.QTE ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":281,"sample":"5B17281","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'What is the true bearing of ____ (call sign) from ____ (call sign)?' ","answers":{"a":"A.QRZ ","b":"B.QSM ","c":"C.QTE ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":282,"sample":"5B17282","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to say 'The name of my station is ____'? ","answers":{"a":"A.QRA ","b":"B.QRL ","c":"C.QRT ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":283,"sample":"5B17283","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to say 'I am busy.  Please do not interfere'? ","answers":{"a":"A.QRL ","b":"B.QST ","c":"C.QVV ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":284,"sample":"5B17284","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to say 'Increase power'? ","answers":{"a":"A.QST ","b":"B.QRT ","c":"C.QRD ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":285,"sample":"5B17285","correct":"C","question":"What Q-signal would be used to say 'Your keying is defective'? ","answers":{"a":"A.QRN ","b":"B.QST ","c":"C.QSD ","d":"D.None of the above"}},{"num":286,"sample":"5B17286","correct":"A","question":"What Q-signal would be used to ask 'I have been unable to break in on your transmission'? ","answers":{"a":"A.QSI ","b":"B.QTH ","c":"C.QRZ ","d":"D.None of the above"}}]
